Today we're going to be learning to play Portal, a game by Valve Software.
A company with which I have no affiliation.
So, here we have the orange portal.
I'm not able to control the orange portal just yet.
Right now the portal gun I have only shoots out blue portals.
I can jump down here and see that there's really no way for me to get out of this space like you would in a normal game.
There's no ladders, there's no staircase, there's nothing like that.
In Portal you have to come up with clever ways to use the portal gun.
I can shoot the blue portal and make an entrance here and then I come out the orange portal which is there on the wall.
Again I can put one here and I'll come out that spot again.
So, the early part of the game encourages you to just play around and see what different kinds of fun you can have with the portal gun.
Now, I need to get over here to the exit where the elevator is and again there's no way for me to get there by conventional means.
And the orange portal is stuck in place, I can't move that one.
What I have to do now is put my blue portal over here and then I can walk into the orange and come out the blue.
And that's chamber 03. Off we go to the next one.